Patrick Carroll

(843) 437-6951

PatrickCarroll.IT@outlook.com

Clearance: <u>Top-Secret SCI</u>

GitHub

https://github.com/PCarroll9500

Certifications

CompTIA Security Plus Microsoft Azure AI Fundamentals Cisco CCNA1 W3 Schools Java Certification '24

Skills

Programming in C, C#, C++, Java, Python, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, SQL, VBA, PowerShell, Batch (Windows), and Bash (Linux)

Projects

Document AI Organization & Scanner

Document classification, renaming, meta-tagging, and organization using AI. Utilized, Microsoft Azure AI Intelligence, Open AI, Python, Java, and JavaScript.

HAZMAT Management

3-person team designed a GUI-based application showcasing Object Oriented Programming principles in Java.

Comparing LLM Context Similarity

Tested the similarities and accuracy of different OpenAl models with Jupyter Notebooks.

Battlezone Remake

A recreation of the 1980s tank simulator done in C/C++ OpenGL, recreated with the iconic Green Vector 3d graphics, particle effects and collision detection.

10+ years of experience across various IT domains. Proven work ethic with a Military background.

Experience

System Software Support Engineer

Jan 2024 - Present

- Reduced PC configuration time by 75% through Windows 10/11 PC deployment via imaging, Windows PE, and batch scripting.
- Created an Al-driven Text-to-Speech add-in for automating PowerPoint training.
- Created documentation to set parameters and update the SQL Server database per customer configurations.

U.S. Navy Reservist IT

Apr 2019 – Present

- Support the Navy part time.
- Trained in Cisco Routers, Switches, End Devices, IPv4 and IPv6 addressing, OSI and TCP/IP models, network protocols, and troubleshooting.
- Qualified in Enlisted Information Warfare.

IT Systems Administration Assistant

Aug 2019 - Dec 2021

- Handled 700+ tickets dealing with the administration of User Accounts, E-mail, Listserv, Security Groups, Distribution Groups, Shared Mailboxes, File Systems, HPC and Active Directory.
- Performed regular back-ups, tape shipment, and audits.

Cable Technician

May 2021 - Aug 2021

- 3-Month Contract in Germany.
- Built Sensitive Compartmented Information Facilities (SCIF's) on military installations, routing cable, conduit, raceway, terminating copper, power, demolition and setting up audio/visual equipment.

U.S. Navy Submarine Radioman

Apr 2014 - Apr 2019

- Analyzed and classified different types of electronic signals for situational awareness.
- Ensured the safety through the operation of the radar and early warning system.
- Qualified 301 Craftsman, 3M, Tag-Out User, Electronic Key Management Systems (KMI), Radar, Electronic Warfare, and Enlisted Submarine Warfare.

Education

Texas A&M–Corpus Christi Bachelor of Science, in Computer Science Focus Systems Programming May 2019 – Dec 2023 (GPA 3.65)

Volunteer & Community Service

Navy Honor Guard Funeral Detail Student Veterans Communication Officer Aug 2022 – Dec 2023 Apr 2019 – Apr 2022